Guide to the collection of bookplates by Timothy Cole
Yale University Arts Library
Collection of bookplates by Timothy Cole
1908-1930
BKP 128
Yale University Arts Library
0.42
(1 box)
The collection includes bookplates designed by Timothy Cole for both individual and institutional patrons.
Cole, Timothy, 1852-1931
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Yale Bookplate Collection was formerly housed in Sterling Memorial Library. The collection was incorporated into the Arts of the Book Collection in 1984 and then moved to the Seeley G. Mudd Library in 1990. In 2011, it was transferred to the Robert B. Haas Family Arts Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Timothy Cole (1852-1931) was an American wood engraver. In addition to designing bookplates, Cole had a long career working in magazine illustration, notably with The Century, and creating printed reproductions of European paintings.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes bookplates designed by Timothy Cole for both individual and institutional patrons.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Bookplates – Individuals, 1915-1930. II. Bookplates – Institutions, 1908-1926. III. Ephemera, undated.
Bookplates, American; Bookplates; Wood engravings
- Bookplates – Individuals, 1915-1930; Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by patron's last name.
  - Beal, Thaddeus R., 1928; 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cole, T., undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Coolidge, Calvin, undated; 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Collins, Philip S., 1928; 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Gribbel, Elizabeth Bancker, 1921; 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood, undated; 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Kling, Flora Gardiner, 1915; 7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes one print inscribed: "For Mr. Kendall Banning from Flora Gardiner Kling, 1915"
  - Knox, Leila Charlton, 1928; 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Leippert, 1929; 4 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Prince, Henry Kimball, 1930; 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Radin, Herman Theodore, undated; 6 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Includes one print inscribed: "To Mr. W.F. Hopson, With the very kindest regards of Herman T. Radin. "
  - Smith, Margaret Pollard, 1927; 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Swett, Carolyn Patten, undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Tiling, Johanna Erika Ruthven von, 1926; 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bookplates – Institutions, 1908-1926; Series II
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Keats-Shelley Memorial, 1908; 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Randolph-Macon Woman's College Art Depar't. Directed by Louise Jordan Smith, 1926; 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Vassar College Library. Timothy Cole Collection, undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Wednesday Book Club, 1921; 1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Ephemera, undated; Series III
  - Reproduction of a portrait of Timothy Cole, engraved on wood by John W. Evans, after a painting by Cole's son Alphaeus P. Cole, N.A., undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 20)